## **Maryam Guppy**

◆ Phone: 501 952 5221 ◆ Email: mguppy34@gmail.com ◆ Austin, TX 78759

◆ LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/maryam-guppy-85ba2726/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/maryam-guppy-85ba2726/</a> ◆ GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/mguppy">https://github.com/mguppy</a>

◆ Portfolio: <a href="https://tranquil-dawn-92403.herokuapp.com/">https://tranquil-dawn-92403.herokuapp.com/</a>

#### **Professional Summary**

Highly motivated Full Stack Web Developer leveraging a background in technology to design, develop, and implement user-friendly applications. Recently earned a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University of Texas of Austin Coding Boot Camp. Experienced in IT audit testing and software testing with the willingness to learn whatever additional skills necessary for a challenging new role. Effective communicator, creative, and a fast learner who enjoys learning new technologies and problem solving.

#### **Technical Skills**

• Languages: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, SQL, NoSQL

• Applications: GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, SAP, Oracle, Epicor, ServiceNow

• Tools: Express, React, Node, Handlebars, Query, Bootstrap, Jest

#### **Projects**

**Jobster** | https://github.com/mguppy/Jobster | https://jobster-group-2.herokuapp.com/aboutus

- Summary: An application where, once signed up and logged in, users can track all of their applications in one place by submitting the appropriate information in our forms. Users can also give the ability to upload resumes and cover letters. Essentially, the application is a one stop shop to keep all job application related materials.
- Role: Project Contributor
- Tools: JavaScript, node.js (and associated packages), HTML, CSS, Handlebars, mySQL, Multer, Cloudinary, Figma, Dbdiagram.io, and Heroku

Pet Seeker | https://github.com/mguppy/pet-seeker | https://brandonnorsworthy.github.io/pet-seeker/

- Summary: An application that enables the user to set preferences based on what type of dog they are looking for. Based on the preferences selected, dogs are pulled back from an API. Another API is used to give the user characteristics like temperament, life-span and weight range based on the breed of the dog. When a user clicks the like button for a pet, the pet information is then stored into local storage so that the user can be taken to the adoption page for that pet.
- Role: Project Contributor
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bulma, Moment, GitHub

### **Experience**

IT Risk and Compliance Analyst, 1/1/2019 to 6/15/2021

**Hanger, Inc.** – Austin, TX

- Identified, documented, and reported audit issues to IT management
- Drove information security risk and process improvement across the organization by working with IT, Finance and Accounting
- Served as liaison between about 20 in-house managers and directors in the IT department and about 15 internal and external financial and operational auditors
- Conducted over 50 quarterly, monthly, and weekly reviews in an efficient manner so that user access within the organization remained appropriate and processes were followed as expected

**Information Systems Auditor**, 10/2017 to 12/31/2018 **Hanger, Inc.** – Austin, TX

• Tested access management, change management, and computer operations controls for over 50 in-scope

- applications as well as their supporting infrastructure
- Performed end to end walkthroughs to understand the requirements necessary for audit testing
- Ensured audit tasks were completed accurately and within established timeframes

# **Information Systems Auditor**, 07/2015 to 09/2017 **KPMG** – Austin, TX

- Performed IT Attestation services for Financial Statement Audits for clients in a variety of industries
- Performed analytical procedures over General Information Technology Controls (GITC) and Application Controls in the area of Access Control, Change Management, and Computer Operations affecting key financial systems
- Conducted client interviews and walkthroughs as well as reviewed client artifacts to determine the design, implementation, and operating effectiveness of each control
- Managed a Prepared By Client (PBC) spreadsheet for client personnel to manage the exchange of documentation to ensure project deadlines were met

### **Analyst/Senior Analyst,** 08/2013 to 07/2015 **Cerner Corporation** – Kansas City, MO

- Implemented the Cerner Health Information Management solution and integration with other solutions purchased for seamless transfer of data and patient information throughout the client facility while complying with HIPAA and meaningful use regulations
- Tasked with analyzing clients' current processes within the HIM department and developed workflows that would fit their future needs. This includes determining the design of the software, building the software, testing the software, and teaching end users how to use the software.

# **Business Intelligence Intern,** 09/2012 to 05/2013 **DaySpring Cards, Inc** – Siloam Springs, AR

- Developed SQL reports to help the business easily articulate their data
- Worked with others in a variety of business processes to understand business requirements that were translated into BI reports
- Performed multiple iterations of testing over business reports to ensure the reports were complete and accurate and met the business requirements

#### **Education**

University of Texas of Austin Coding Boot Camp: Full Stack Web Development Certificate, September 2021

**Bachelor of Science:** Information Systems, 2013

University of Arkansas, Fayetteville - Fayetteville, AR